<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Remote, Self-Education, No-Burnout &amp; More. Blog by Ninel Bolotova</title>
    <link>https://ninel.work/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Remote, Self-Education, No-Burnout &amp; More. Blog by Ninel Bolotova</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ninel.work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Start a Successful Study Group Online? Challenges &amp; Tips</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/start-successful-study-group-online-challenges-tips-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/start-successful-study-group-online-challenges-tips-guide/</guid>
      <description>To absorb and retain the knowledge better, you need to actively use it. One of the ways to do it is by interacting with your peers, explaining things to them and hearing their perspectives. A study group could be a fun and efficient way of preparing for an exam or achieving another learning goal.
Joining or starting an online study group is easy – there are millions of peers around the world you could connect with, and many of them have their goals and interests aligned with yours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find the Best Online Course for You? 6 Points to Consider</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-find-best-online-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-find-best-online-course/</guid>
      <description>There are so many courses out there: free and paid, instructor-led and self-paced, lasting from a few hours to a few weeks or months.
Whatever topic you&amp;rsquo;re looking for, you&amp;rsquo;ll find dozens of courses. Even if the topic is obscure, you&amp;rsquo;ll likely find more than one.
How do you choose which one to go with? If it&amp;rsquo;s a paid course, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to gamble your money, but free courses require investments as well – your time and energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Pass the Certification Exam on the First Try – Study Tips</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-pass-certification-exam-test-first-try-tips-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-pass-certification-exam-test-first-try-tips-techniques/</guid>
      <description>So, you figured out why you want to get certified, checked and compared the options, and chose a credential you want to pursue. It would be great to pass the test the first time you attempt it. Is there a way to prepare that would guarantee such success?
I&amp;rsquo;m not giving you a 100% success guarantee (and you should be wary of people who claim they do). But I&amp;rsquo;ll share an approach that would increase your chances greatly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 11:15:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>The site collects Google Analytics data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Proctored Testing at Home: Pros &amp; Cons. Where to Take Your Exam?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/online-proctored-testing-pros-cons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/online-proctored-testing-pros-cons/</guid>
      <description>One of the silver linings to the 2020 COVID pandemic was that the certification providers became much more open to online testing. Now everyone offers this option, so you could take a test from the comfort of your own home.
There are a few caveats, though. I took my certification tests online, and I&amp;rsquo;ll likely continue to do so in the future. But every time at a certain point I wished I were in a test center instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 6 Cybersecurity Certification Providers&#39; Recertification Costs</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/top-cybersecurity-providers-recertification-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/top-cybersecurity-providers-recertification-cost/</guid>
      <description>So, you decided that it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to get a cybersecurity certification. But which one should you go for?
While obtaining a certification is quite an endeavor, that’s only the first step. To keep it active, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to pay annual fees and submit continuous education units based on the issuers’ requirements. Otherwise, your hard-earned credential will expire, and it will be forbidden and unethical to introduce yourself as a certification holder by listing it in your CV or profile headline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 11:15:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can get in touch with me on Twitter or LinkedIn, or write me an email: contactREMOVE@ninel.work</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work with me</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/work-with-ninel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 11:16:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/work-with-ninel/</guid>
      <description>I provide various services as a freelancer, including but not limited to:
project management creating and optimizing workflows in remote environment reviewing and hiring the best contractors in various fields implementing Agile methodologies setting up and customizing E-commerce stores, mainly Shopify productivity coaching Get in touch with me to book a free 30-min discovery call:
contactREMOVE@ninel.work</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Ninel Bolotova</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 11:15:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/about/</guid>
      <description>On this blog, I share articles about self-education, remote work, certifications and continuous education, and other related subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Getting Certified Worth It? Do the Benefits Outweigh the Costs?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>If the job you seek requires a license, then making a decision is easy – you don&amp;rsquo;t really have a choice. Licensure and certification are both means of verifying your skills and expertise, but they have some distinct differences.
In a nutshell, a license is issued by a government authority and is legally required to practice in a field or hold a certain title. Certification is voluntary, serving as a reassurance to your peers and clients that you meet specific qualifications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
