<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal and Professional Development via Life-Long Learning</title>
    <link>https://ninel.work/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Personal and Professional Development via Life-Long Learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ninel.work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hire a ClickUp Expert – Advanced Workflow Setup &amp; Automation</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/services/hire-clickup-expert-workspace-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/services/hire-clickup-expert-workspace-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you planning to migrate to ClickUp from another project management platform? Or is this your team’s first time using a PM tool for collaboration, and you need help getting started?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or maybe you&amp;rsquo;re already using ClickUp and want to streamline your operations with automation?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m Ninel, a workflow architect and integration specialist. I work with individuals and companies to design, optimize, and automate processes in ClickUp and other project management tools, solving challenges and improving efficiency every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hire a Monday.com Expert – Personalized Workflow Setup &amp; Automation</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/services/hire-monday-expert-setup-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/services/hire-monday-expert-setup-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you planning to move to Monday.com from another project management software? Or is it the first PM tool your team is about to use for collaboration, and you&amp;rsquo;re looking for assistance with the initial setup?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps you’d like to streamline your current processes in Monday with automation?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m Ninel, a workflow architect and integration expert. I help individuals and companies set up and optimize their process flows in Monday.com and other project management tools, and solve various challenges along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiring Competent Freelancers and Employees: the Screening Questions</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/hire-competent-freelancers-employees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/hire-competent-freelancers-employees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever spent hours going through job post applications and interviewing candidates, only to feel that you&amp;rsquo;re still not confident about who to choose?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had candidates not showing up for calls without much explanation? Or situations when it became apparent minutes into a call that they aren&amp;rsquo;t who they were presenting themselves as in their cover letter and CV? Or, worse, when it became apparent later in the process, maybe even after you hired them?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workflow Setup in Any Task Management Tool: Key Questions</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/workflow-setup-principles-trello-asana-clickup-notion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/workflow-setup-principles-trello-asana-clickup-notion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you use or plan to use Trello, ClickUp, Monday, Notion or another project management system for your workflows, there are structural and operational points that need to be considered to build an efficient and productive workspace.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you design your workspace architecture and flows, answer the questions below. If you have bottlenecks in your workflows, those questions will help you zero in on their causes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you decide that assistance from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/workflow-certifications-project-management-software/&#34;&gt;certified workflow expert&lt;/a&gt; would be beneficial, I could help out  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/workflow-setup-automation-expert-specialist-hire/&#34;&gt;with workspace setup, optimization and integration&lt;/a&gt;, so feel free to get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Can I Trust and not Get Burned? Red and Green Flags</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/who-to-trust-red-green-flags/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/who-to-trust-red-green-flags/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be great to live in a world where you never have to question others’ reliability and intentions?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the real world, however, we constantly need to gauge the trustworthiness of strangers and friends alike. Every new situation, every decision that involves another person is a leap of faith to some degree.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is there a way to tell for sure whether you can trust someone or not? While there’s no rule that would give a certain guarantee, there are points to look out for to minimize the chances of being fooled or disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines for Efficient Workflow Automation in Project Management</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/workflow-automation-project-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/workflow-automation-project-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a few components to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/workflow-setup-principles-trello-asana-clickup-notion/&#34;&gt;setting up smooth and efficient workflows in PM software&lt;/a&gt;. One of them is automation – when used to its full potential, it provides a great boost to various components of the flow and improves the quality of life of the team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, I’ll dive into comparison of what different PM tools offer with their automation. Use the Contents section below to jump to the tool you consider using in your workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workflow Setup, Automation and Integration Expert for Hire</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/workflow-setup-automation-expert-specialist-hire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/workflow-setup-automation-expert-specialist-hire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/workflow-setup-automation-expert-specialist-hire-hero.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;Hire a certified workflow expert to help with setting up and optimizing flows in Trello, Asana, Monday.com, Notion, ClickUp, and other PM software.&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I currently specialize in workflow architecture and integration, I also provide &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/personal-professional-development-coaching/&#34;&gt;coaching for individuals and teams&lt;/a&gt;, help with hiring the best person for the job, and solve problems in general.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I like challenges, so if there’s a problem in your organization that someone with my skills could help with tackling, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/contact&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; and let’s discuss it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Become a Notion Certified Consultant: a Practical Guide</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/notion-certified-exam-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/notion-certified-exam-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notion is a popular productivity software used by millions of teams and individuals worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the Notion certification program, you could obtain badges and eventually become a Notion Certified Consultant, landing into &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/consulting-partners&#34;&gt;Notion Consulting Partners registry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notion certifications are free – but, while there are no exam fees, there are a few caveats to obtaining the badges, and there are some strings attached if you decide to pursue the status of a Notion Consulting Partner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disciplined Agile Certifications - Is DASSM Worth It?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/disciplined-agile-certifications-dassm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/disciplined-agile-certifications-dassm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you heard about Disciplined Agile for the first time, your first thought probably was:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“What? Yet another Agile framework on top of SAFe, LeSS, and a dozen more already out there?”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, at this point, you most likely know that DA embraces the existing frameworks and aims to help you choose the best approach for your current needs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But does Disciplined Agile provide substantial benefits? Should you delve deeper into learning it?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impostor Syndrome: How to Overcome It for Good?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/impostor-syndrome-how-overcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/impostor-syndrome-how-overcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Impostor syndrome is more common than you might think. For all you know, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7174434/&#34;&gt;over half of your friends and colleagues&lt;/a&gt; might be experiencing it – and saying nothing, because, of course, they don’t want to be outed as impostors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The impostor phenomenon could be a big impediment to your career growth – or worse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being reluctant to raise your rates or ask for a promotion is one thing. But when a person works in an environment they hate, feeling like they got to that position by chance, and things will only get worse for them if they leave – that is dangerous for mental and even physical health.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Criticism at Work and at Home: How to Handle It Constructively</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-handle-deal-with-criticism-work-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-handle-deal-with-criticism-work-family/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes being told that their behavior is wrong, their work is incompetent, or their life choices are faulty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When those things are told in a rude, condescending manner, we like them even less.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How to deal with criticism at work and home and minimize its negative emotional impact?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And how to process every piece of criticism into valuable information that helps you grow as a professional and as a person?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ClickUp, Jira, Notion &amp; More: Which Certification Should I Get?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/workflow-certifications-project-management-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/workflow-certifications-project-management-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you ever have this “duh” feeling when you learned about a feature or shortcut months into using a piece of software?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many project and workflow management tools on the market. ClickUp, Jira, and Notion are some of the most popular ones, but there are many others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is it worth investing your time in learning more about the tools that you use and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/workflow-setup-principles-trello-asana-clickup-notion/&#34;&gt;principles of organizing efficient workflows&lt;/a&gt;? Definitely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Your Online, Remote or Tech Job to Family and Friends</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/explain-job-online-remote-family-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/explain-job-online-remote-family-friends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you tell people what your job is, do you usually get nods of recognition or baffled looks?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the modern world, there are roles and occupations that didn’t exist a few decades ago or got a new spin as more and more people switched to working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps you have a profession that has been around for a while but doesn’t immediately bring an image to mind, like “a doctor” or “a construction worker” would.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work-Life Balance or Integration? How to Maintain When WFH</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/find-maintain-work-life-balance-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/find-maintain-work-life-balance-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The question of work-life balance became especially topical when many people switched to working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How to maintain the balance between work and home lives when your home &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; your workplace? Is it possible to separate them? And is it necessary?..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Work from home, or WFH, is a blessing if managed successfully – but it requires a good deal of self-awareness, as well as making some conscious choices that aren’t always easy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Rules of Effective Delegation of Tasks and Authority</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/effective-delegation-tasks-authority-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/effective-delegation-tasks-authority-workplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you the best guy or gal for the job?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you’re qualified. But for the overall outcome, would it be best if &lt;em&gt;you’re&lt;/em&gt; the one doing a  certain task?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Successful delegation allows for more work to be done better, empowers others, and helps you &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/find-maintain-work-life-balance-home/&#34;&gt;maintain a healthy work-life balance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unsuccessful delegation leads to lots of rework, broken trust, and losses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ability to delegate is especially important for project managers, business owners, and other people in leadership positions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Burnout &amp; Mental Exhaustion: an Actionable Guide</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/burnout-mental-exhaustion-how-to-overcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/burnout-mental-exhaustion-how-to-overcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You’re depleted. You’ve had enough.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There’s barely any fuel left in your energy tank, so you’re squeezing blood out of your veins to keep the car of your life running for another mile.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does it sound familiar?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll discuss:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How to tell if you’re burned out&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Common burnout causes: what’s your primary cause?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Strategies and tips for dealing with burnout&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How to recover from burnout mentally and physically&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/burnout-mental-exhaustion-how-to-overcome-hero.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;How to tell you&amp;#39;re burned out, and how to deal with and recover from a burnout?&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;photo by @tara-winstead on Pexels&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Actionable Personal Development Coaching Packages. Services</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/personal-professional-development-coaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/personal-professional-development-coaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I offer coaching to help you become more productive and efficient, develop good habits, and learn skills that would &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/how-life-success-factors/&#34;&gt;make you more successful&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Developing an actionable plan with measurable goals.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Having an honest discussion about your current impediments and how to deal with them in your particular circumstances.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Accountability partnership.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Improving focus, productivity and efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;personal-development-coaching-options&#34;&gt;Personal development coaching options&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#value-based-coaching-intro&#34;&gt;Value-based 30-minute coaching intro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#on-demand-talk-personal-coaching-package&#34;&gt;The “&lt;strong&gt;On-demand talk&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/a&gt; coaching package: 240 minutes of one-on-one coaching.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#messaging-mentor-personal-coaching-package&#34;&gt;The “&lt;strong&gt;Messaging mentor&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/a&gt; coaching package: 100 minutes of live coaching + text chat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#single-personal-development-coaching-session&#34;&gt;A one-off personal development coaching session&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You could click the links to jump down to the options for more information. But if you haven’t done so already, I encourage you to read the rest of the page to see if I could provide value in your particular situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Set and Maintain Healthy Boundaries: The Key Factors</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-set-maintain-develop-boundaries-strong-healthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-set-maintain-develop-boundaries-strong-healthy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What are boundaries, and why are they so important for your personal and professional &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/how-life-success-factors/&#34;&gt;life success and satisfaction&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The laws of the state are explicit, and if someone breaks a law, they’ll be &lt;strong&gt;prosecuted&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ethics and morale are widely agreed on in society, and if someone acts unethically, they’ll face &lt;strong&gt;social consequences&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But the individual, personal boundaries have no universal rules. There’s a consensus on some things: for example, asking strangers about their personal life is intrusive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Consistency and Self-Discipline: 5 Actionable Tips</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-improve-consistency-tips-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-improve-consistency-tips-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To achieve our goals, we need to do things repeatedly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practicing day after day&lt;/strong&gt; to maintain and improve our professional skills and physical shape.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repeatedly saying &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; to people who ask for more than we can – or are willing – to give at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constantly fighting&lt;/strong&gt; destructive behaviors and habits.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Success isn&amp;rsquo;t a one-time feat, it&amp;rsquo;s compounded from small building blocks. And the foundation for life success is consistency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to 10x Your Chances to Achieve Success in Life</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-life-success-factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-life-success-factors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, here&amp;rsquo;s the formula for achieving success in anything:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success = Effort x Tools x Consistency x Talent x Mindset&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ok, that looks vague. How do you actually use it in your life?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How do you improve each of those points to increase your chances of success tenfold or even much more?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at each of the points in the formula and talk about some important conditions to use it efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taking the PRINCE2 Exams Without a Textbook: an Experiment</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/prince2-agile-exam-taking-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/prince2-agile-exam-taking-experiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You need to answer barely over half of the questions to pass the test.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t sound like a challenge. Or does it?..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I first learned that the pass mark for PRINCE2 certifications by Axelos is about 55%, it almost struck me as an unfair advantage. For example, the passing score for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/psm-1-certification-exam-preparation/&#34;&gt;Professional Scrum Master exam&lt;/a&gt; is 85%. That exam, however, doesn’t have any kind of proctoring.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PRINCE2 is proctored, but on the Practitioner level, you’re allowed to use the official manual. At 55%, is it even possible to fail?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRINCE2 Agile: Is It Worth It, and How to Pass the Exam</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/prince2-agile-certification-exam-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/prince2-agile-certification-exam-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRINCE2 Agile is an extension of the PRINCE2 method, tailored to an Agile environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given that PRINCE2 is one of the most popular certifications today, does the same go for PRINCE2 Agile? Is it a certification you should obtain?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PRINCE stands for “Projects in &lt;strong&gt;controlled&lt;/strong&gt; environments”. “Controlled” is associated with “strict, pre-defined”, and Agile is the opposite of that. How could PRINCE2 be Agile?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That’s what we’ll discuss today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How do the PRINCE2 method and the Agile approach gel together?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Should you pursue the PRINCE2 Agile certification?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How to prepare for and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/how-pass-certification-exam-test-first-try-tips-techniques/&#34;&gt;successfully pass the certification exams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/prince2-agile-certification-exam-preparation-hero.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;PRINCE2 Agile is a project management certification by Axelos. What is it about, and should you get it?&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;photo by @jessbaileydesign on Pexels&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A 30-day Self-Improvement Challenge - Updated Monthly</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/self-improvement-challenge-personal-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/self-improvement-challenge-personal-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s the personal growth challenge for this month. What were your favorite and least favorite tasks? How many days did you complete? Do you have some ideas for the upcoming challenges?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/contact/&#34;&gt;Get in touch&lt;/a&gt; and let me know!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;pinnable&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/30-day-personal-growth-self-improvement-development-challenge.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;A 30-day self-growth challenge for this month&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-dont-use-your-phone-for-1-hour-before-going-to-bed&#34;&gt;1. Don’t use your phone for 1 hour before going to bed&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Put down your phone and other electronic devices an hour before you plan to go to sleep. Mute all notifications so it doesn’t make sounds or buzz.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interviewing Alexander Hardt, a Professional Scrum Trainer</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/interview-hardt-business-analysis-scrum-trainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/interview-hardt-business-analysis-scrum-trainer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexhardt23/&#34;&gt;Alexander Hardt&lt;/a&gt; is a business agility coach with over 20 years of experience with Scrum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scrum.org/alexander-hardt&#34;&gt;Professional Scrum Trainer&lt;/a&gt;, Alexander gives classes on almost all certifications currently available at Scrum.org.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ll talk about:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The journey to where he is today&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What role luck played in Alexander’s success – and how do we define “success”?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Advice to the past self and the aspirations for the future.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/interview-hardt-business-analysis-scrum-trainer-hero.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;Interviewing a professional scrum trainer and a business agility coach. What is his story?&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-software-developer-to-an-agile-coach&#34;&gt;From software developer to an Agile Coach&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ninel: I read that you wanted to become a detective in your childhood. How did you become a software developer, and, eventually, an Scrum Trainer?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PMP Certification Exam Preparation: the Full Guide</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/pmp-certification-exam-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/pmp-certification-exam-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, here we are at last.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You’re sure that &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/is-project-management-right-for-me/&#34;&gt;project management is the right career for you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You feel that you acquired enough professional experience to apply for the most famous project management certification in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And it’s a great time to do it! Today, the PMP certification is more accessible than it has ever been before:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Simplified work experience requirements.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An option to take a proctored test remotely.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Since early 2023, the pricing is region-based, so the exam got more affordable for many potential applicants.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You’re going to get ready for the PMP exam and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/how-pass-certification-exam-test-first-try-tips-techniques/&#34;&gt;pass it on the first try&lt;/a&gt;. Let’s do this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PMP Audit Survival Guide: How to Pass the PMP Audit in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-pass-pmp-audit-pmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-pass-pmp-audit-pmi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To maintain the standards and enhance the credibility of its certifications, PMI randomly audits a  number of applicants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Project Management Professional is the most popular certification by PMI, so the audit is usually discussed in the context of PMP. But those who apply for CAPM, PMI-ACP, and other certifications could be audited as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If selected for audit, they’ll have to present proof of work experience, academic education, and contact hours they listed on their application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAPM: Is It Worth It, and How to Prepare for The Exam?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/capm-certification-exam-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/capm-certification-exam-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Certified Associate in Project Management is an entry-level certification by a globally recognized authority, Project Management Institute (PMI).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Will it help with your career, and how to prepare for the CAPM exam?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll talk about:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The benefits and costs of getting the CAPM certification&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How the exam changed in 2023&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How to study for CAPM to successfully pass it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alternatives to CAPM and the next steps after obtaining the certification&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/capm-certification-exam-preparation-hero.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;Is CAPM certification relevant? What are the benefits of obtaining it?&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;photo by @pavel-danilyuk on Pexels&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is PMP Certification Worth It in 2025? Costs vs. Benefits</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/is-pmp-certification-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/is-pmp-certification-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Project Management Professional certification is the most recognized PM credential worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You most likely saw the PMP abbreviation way before you started looking into obtaining a certification, and probably even before you &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/is-project-management-right-for-me/&#34;&gt;took on a project management role&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the world adopts Agile approaches more and more, you might be wondering: is PMP still relevant?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The short answer is “yes”. The certification issuer, PMI, constantly adapts. With the recent exam modifications and the introduction of a flexible pricing structure, taking the PMP exam is a great option for anyone who fits the eligibility requirements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PMP vs. PRINCE2: Which Certification Should You Get in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/pmp-prince2-certifications-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/pmp-prince2-certifications-differences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me make a few assumptions about you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I assume that at this point you’re sure that &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/is-project-management-right-for-me/&#34;&gt;project management is the right occupation&lt;/a&gt; for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most probably, you already work as a PM and want to enhance your professional profile and gain new knowledge by &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/&#34;&gt;getting a professional certification&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PMP is recognized worldwide, but PRINCE2 is also a well-known and respected project management certification.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll talk about their similarities and differences, which one is harder to get, and which of them will be the most relevant for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRINCE2 Certification: The Ultimate Exam Preparation Guide</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/prince2-certification-exam-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/prince2-certification-exam-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoiler alert&lt;/strong&gt;: the PRINCE2 Foundation and Practitioner exams themselves are relatively easy, as far as the certification exams go. You need to get a little over half of the questions right to pass, versus around 70% for &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/pmp-certification-exam-preparation/&#34;&gt;PMP&lt;/a&gt; or 85% for &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/psm-1-certification-exam-preparation/&#34;&gt;PSM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But figuring out the exam cost and actually booking it is less than straightforward…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/is-project-management-right-for-me/&#34;&gt;Is the project manager career a good fit for me?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll talk about:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Project Management Right for Me? 10 Questions to Consider</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/is-project-management-right-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/is-project-management-right-for-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Project Manager is a well-paying job full of exciting challenges, but it requires certain personal skills. Give honest answers to the questions below to see if a PM role is a good fit for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we talk about the traits that great project managers have, we discuss the responsibilities, struggles and delights that the role entails.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The last section tackles more questions related to the project manager job, like what the salary is, the difference between Project and Product Management, and what is required to launch your career as a project manager.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Product Management Books for Beginners and Professionals</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/best-product-management-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/best-product-management-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s the reference list of practical and insightful books on product management to read this year:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Cracking-Career-Frameworks-Practices-Interview-ebook/dp/B08TQ89LKB&#34;&gt;Cracking the PM Career&lt;/a&gt; (2021)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Professional-Product-Owner-Leveraging-Competitive/dp/0134686470&#34;&gt;The Professional Product Owner&lt;/a&gt; (2018)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Lean-Product-Playbook-Innovate-Products-ebook/dp/B00SZ638C8&#34;&gt;The Lean Product Playbook&lt;/a&gt; (2015)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1119551447/&#34;&gt;Testing Business Ideas&lt;/a&gt; (2019)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Strategize-Product-Strategy-Roadmap-Practices/dp/0993499201&#34;&gt;Strategize&lt;/a&gt; (2022)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/INSPIRED-Create-Tech-Products-Customers-ebook/dp/B077NRB36N&#34;&gt;Inspired&lt;/a&gt; (2017)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01H4G2J1U/&#34;&gt;The Mom Test&lt;/a&gt; (2016)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Escaping-Build-Trap-Effective-Management/dp/149197379X&#34;&gt;Escaping the Build Trap&lt;/a&gt; (2018)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Hooked-How-Build-Habit-Forming-Products/dp/1591847788&#34;&gt;Hooked&lt;/a&gt; (2014)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Product-Led-Growth-Build-Product-Itself-ebook/dp/B07P6288ZF&#34;&gt;Product-Led Growth&lt;/a&gt; (2019)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They range from just starting your career in product management to bringing innovation at an enterprise level.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSPO I, II and III: How to Prepare for and Pass the Exams</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/pspo-certification-exam-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/pspo-certification-exam-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Product Owner isn&amp;rsquo;t a job title but an accountability in Scrum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a person responsible for maximizing value by defining the product goal, optimizing the product backlog, turning feedback into actionable items, and guiding the team toward the product vision.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This requires a combination of business acumen, market awareness, leadership skills, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/develop-intuition-learning-self-awareness/&#34;&gt;intuition&lt;/a&gt;, and other factors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Will obtaining the Professional Scrum Product Owner certification prove – and improve – those skills? Is getting PSPO &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/&#34;&gt;worth it&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thanks for subscribing!</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/thanks-for-subscribing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/thanks-for-subscribing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy to have you here! You&amp;rsquo;re among the first to show interest in the e-book : )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s actually still in progress: given that the site doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much traffic yet and the average visitor-to-subscriber ratio, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure people would attempt downloading the book any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;ve been prioritizing articles to add more content to the website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But once people start subscribing, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to finish the e-book as soon as possible and send it over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cynefin Framework for Decision-Making Explained and Applied</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/cynefin-framework-decision-making-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/cynefin-framework-decision-making-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What do I do now?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Should I swiftly &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/develop-intuition-learning-self-awareness/&#34;&gt;act on a hunch&lt;/a&gt; or gather more information? Should I seek help? Is there an obvious solution that I’m missing?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cynefin (spelled “kuh-NEV-in”) is a “sense-making” framework. It aims to help with the understanding of what kind of a situation you’re in and what is the optimal course of action in this situation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A solution that works in one context could be worthless or even harmful in another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the Scrum Master Role Right for Me? 7 Questions to Consider</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/is-the-scrum-master-role-right-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/is-the-scrum-master-role-right-for-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scrum Master is a lucrative role. It has good earning potential. Obtaining a Scrum Master certification, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/psm-csm-which-scrum-certification-best/&#34;&gt;PSM or CSM&lt;/a&gt;, is achievable within a short period of time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, while anyone could take the role, not everyone will be happy or successful performing it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Give honest answers to the following questions to see if the Scrum Master role is a good fit for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/is-the-scrum-master-role-right-for-me-hero.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;Is the Scrum Master role a good fit for you? Answer those questions and come to your own conclusions&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;photo by @olly on Pexels&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing an Agile Mindset: Key Values and Principles Applied</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/develop-agile-mindset-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/develop-agile-mindset-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agile methodologies are successful when people involved share certain values and principles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agile mindset is an approach that focuses on learning, action, collaboration, adaptation, and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll discuss what the Agile mindset is, how it’s different from Lean and Growth mindsets, and how it could be implemented beyond your workspace.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/develop-agile-mindset-guide-hero.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;What is the Agile mindset and how to develop it? How is it different from Lean and Growth mindsets?&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;photo by @austindistel on Unsplash&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should I Renew My Professional Certification or Let It Expire?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/renew-certification-or-let-it-expire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/renew-certification-or-let-it-expire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your professional certification will expire soon, but you have doubts about whether you should renew it or not.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maybe you don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or inspiration to earn the Continuing Education units your certification provider requires. Or perhaps you don&amp;rsquo;t feel that this credential was particularly useful to you, and don&amp;rsquo;t want to pay the renewal costs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll break down the value your credential has been providing you or could provide you in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Get SEU for CSM Renewal: Free and Paid Options</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-to-get-seu-for-csm-renewal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-to-get-seu-for-csm-renewal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Certified Scrum Master credential by Scrum Alliance has to be renewed every 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the end of the 2-year cycle, you need to pay a $100 fee and submit 20 Scrum Educational Units (SEUs). 1 SEU equals 1 hour practicing and studying Scrum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will discuss easy and challenging, free and paid ways to earn SEUs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/how-get-seu-csm-renewal-free-hero.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;What are the ways of earning the Scrum Education Units - SEUs to renew the CSM certification?&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;photo by @sickhews on Unsplash&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSM III certification: Actionable Guide to Pass the Exam</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/psm-3-certification-exam-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/psm-3-certification-exam-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PSM III certification exam is the ultimate challenge for Scrum practitioners. Out of all people who passed the PSM I test, only 0.2% went all the way up to level three.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/PSM-holders-Count-Scrum-org.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;Number of Scrum.org Professional Scrum Master certification holders on each of the three levels&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;Screenshot from Scrum.org&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are just over 1000 people in the entire world who obtained the PSM III certification.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But that statistic doesn&amp;rsquo;t show an untold number of people who attempted the PSM 3 exam, failed, and were discouraged from ever trying again. I won&amp;rsquo;t let this happen to you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSM II Certification: How to Pass the Exam Successfully</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/psm-2-certification-exam-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/psm-2-certification-exam-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PSM II is the advanced Scrum Master certification exam by Scrum.org. While &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/psm-1-certification-exam-preparation/&#34;&gt;PSM I is validating your knowledge&lt;/a&gt; of the Scrum framework elements, PSM II tests your understanding and interpretation of the Scrum Guide principles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re choosing between CSM and PSM, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/psm-csm-which-scrum-certification-best/&#34;&gt;how PSM 2 compares to A-CSM&lt;/a&gt;, the second level of Scrum Mastery certification by Scrum Alliance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, you’ll find practical tips on how to prepare for the PSM II exam and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/how-pass-certification-exam-test-first-try-tips-techniques/&#34;&gt;pass it on the first try&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSM I Certification: How to Prepare for and Pass the Exam</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/psm-1-certification-exam-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/psm-1-certification-exam-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The PSM I exam tests your knowledge of the Scrum framework and the Scrum Master accountability in particular, as defined in the Scrum Guide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Should you go for this certification? And what preparation techniques to use to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/how-pass-certification-exam-test-first-try-tips-techniques/&#34;&gt;pass your exam on the first try&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/psm-1-certification-exam-preparation-hero.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;How to prepare for the PSM I certification exam and successfully pass it on the first try?&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;photo by @ekaterina-bolovtsova on Pexels&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;toc&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;label for=&#34;show_contents&#34;&gt;CONTENTS  &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  ⇅&lt;/label&gt;&#xA;  &lt;input id=&#34;show_contents&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34; name=&#34;_toc&#34;&gt;&#xA;         &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#is-psm-i-certification-worth-it&#34;&gt;Is PSM I certification worth it?&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;      &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-popular-is-the-psm-i-certification&#34;&gt;How popular is the PSM I certification?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#psm-i-exam-and-preparation-cost&#34;&gt;PSM I exam and preparation cost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-hard-is-the-psm-1-exam&#34;&gt;How hard is the PSM 1 exam?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#is-the-psm-i-exam-open-book-or-proctored&#34;&gt;Is the PSM I exam open book or proctored?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-the-difference-between-psm-i-and-psm-ii&#34;&gt;What is the difference between PSM I and PSM II?&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;      &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#can-i-skip-psm-i-and-take-psm-ii-directly&#34;&gt;Can I skip PSM I and take PSM II directly?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#mindset-to-prepare-for-the-psm-i-exam&#34;&gt;Mindset to prepare for the PSM I exam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#caution-old-versions-of-the-scrum-guide-vs-the-2020-version&#34;&gt;Caution: old versions of the Scrum Guide vs. the 2020 version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#topics-and-keywords-for-psm-1&#34;&gt;Topics and keywords for PSM 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#psm-i-preparation-courses-and-exam-simulators&#34;&gt;PSM I preparation courses and exam simulators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#recommended-books-to-prepare-for-the-psm-1-certification&#34;&gt;Recommended books to prepare for the PSM 1 certification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/nav&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-psm-i-certification-worth-it&#34;&gt;Is PSM I certification worth it?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/&#34;&gt;Getting certified is worth it&lt;/a&gt;, first and foremost, because of the knowledge, insights and skills you’ll gain during the preparation.You will become a better Scrum Master and a more well-rounded professional.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Free Webinars to Prepare for Scrum Certification Exams</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/free-scrum-agile-webinars-prepare-certification-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/free-scrum-agile-webinars-prepare-certification-exam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my PSM exam preparation, I went through nearly all the materials on Scrum.org learning paths – Scrum Master, Product Owner, Software Developer, and Agile Leader.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Among the articles, books, and shorter videos, there were 12 full-width webinars that I diligently watched and learned a lot from. Topics they cover:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;working the Agile way&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;building a successful product&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;being a leader&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If these align with your goals, these webinars will give you insight and inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing Intuition With Learning and Self-Awareness</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/develop-intuition-learning-self-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/develop-intuition-learning-self-awareness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Does your &amp;ldquo;gut feeling&amp;rdquo; ever lie to you?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How many times did you wish you trusted your initial instinct? Or regretted the decision you made without thinking it through because at the moment it felt &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo;? Are you irritated that ` you keep overthinking things, and the opportunities slip away?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Intuition is a spontaneous insight without conscious reasoning. It&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily correct. But when we talk about developing intuition, the intent is learning to make quick judgments that would bring desirable outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSM vs. CSM: which Scrum certification is the best choice?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/psm-csm-which-scrum-certification-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/psm-csm-which-scrum-certification-best/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scrum is a framework for solving complex problems. It’s mainly used for software and product development but could be applied to any project with evolving requirements and short feedback loops.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obtaining a Scrum certification is a way of transitioning into a new role, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/develop-agile-mindset-guide/&#34;&gt;developing an Agile mindset&lt;/a&gt;, and improving your practical application of the framework.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Professional Scrum Master by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scrum.org/&#34;&gt;Scrum.org&lt;/a&gt; and Certified Scrum Master by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scrumalliance.org/&#34;&gt;Scrum Alliance&lt;/a&gt; are the most popular certifications for people planning to take on the Scrum Master role or already working in that role and wishing to formalize and improve their knowledge and practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn From Zero With the Right Questions. Online Research Strategy</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/online-research-strategy-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/online-research-strategy-efficient/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Where do I even start?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a question you&amp;rsquo;re asking yourself when you want to venture into something you have little prior experience with. Learning a language? &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/&#34;&gt;Getting a professional certification&lt;/a&gt;? Starting a blog? Becoming a successful lawyer? You name it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So many options, possible paths, opportunities, pitfalls, and dead ends.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How can you be sure you won&amp;rsquo;t make some silly mistake that would cost you time or money? Is there a way to avoid the wrong turns and find an optimal way toward your target goal?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Start a Successful Study Group Online? Challenges &amp; Tips</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/start-successful-study-group-online-challenges-tips-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/start-successful-study-group-online-challenges-tips-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To absorb and retain the knowledge better, you need to actively use it. One of the ways to do it is by interacting with your peers, explaining things to them and hearing their perspectives. A study group could be a fun and efficient way of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/how-pass-certification-exam-test-first-try-tips-techniques/&#34;&gt;preparing for an exam&lt;/a&gt; or achieving another learning goal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Joining or starting an online study group is easy – there are millions of peers around the world you could connect with, and many of them have their goals and interests aligned with yours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Find the Best Online Course for You? 6 Points to Consider</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-find-best-online-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-find-best-online-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are so many courses out there: free and paid, instructor-led and self-paced, lasting from a few hours to a few weeks or months.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whatever topic you&amp;rsquo;re looking for, you&amp;rsquo;ll find dozens of courses. Even if the topic is obscure, you&amp;rsquo;ll likely find more than one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How do you choose which one to go with? If it&amp;rsquo;s a paid course, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to gamble your money, but free courses require investments as well – your time and energy. How to choose an informative course you&amp;rsquo;ll feel happy taking and could successfully finish?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Pass the Certification Exam on the First Try – Study Tips</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-pass-certification-exam-test-first-try-tips-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-pass-certification-exam-test-first-try-tips-techniques/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you figured out &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/&#34;&gt;why you want to get certified&lt;/a&gt;, checked and compared the options, and chose a credential you want to pursue. It would be great to pass the test the first time you attempt it. Is there a way to prepare that would guarantee such success?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not giving you a 100% success guarantee (and you should be wary of people who claim they do). But I&amp;rsquo;ll share an approach that would increase your chances greatly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 11:15:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This website uses a few third-party services. Their privacy policies are linked below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, and Google Adsense: &lt;a href=&#34;https://policies.google.com/privacy&#34;&gt;Google Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ezoic Ads. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ezoic.com/privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Ezoic Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ConvertKit for newsletter subscription. &lt;a href=&#34;https://convertkit.com/privacy&#34;&gt;ConvertKit Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Proctored Testing at Home: Pros &amp; Cons. Where to Take Your Exam?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/online-proctored-testing-pros-cons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/online-proctored-testing-pros-cons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the silver linings to the 2020 COVID pandemic was that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/&#34;&gt;certification providers&lt;/a&gt; became much more open to online testing. Now everyone offers this option, so you could take a test from the comfort of your own home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are a few caveats, though. I took my certification tests online, and I&amp;rsquo;ll likely continue to do so in the future. But every time at a certain point I wished I were in a test center instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 6 Cybersecurity Certification Providers&#39; Recertification Costs</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/top-cybersecurity-providers-recertification-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/top-cybersecurity-providers-recertification-cost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/&#34;&gt;decided that it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea&lt;/a&gt; to get a cybersecurity certification. But which one should you go for?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While obtaining a certification is quite an endeavor, that’s only the first step. To keep it active, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to pay annual fees and submit continuous education units based on the issuers’ requirements. Otherwise, your hard-earned credential will expire, and it will be forbidden and unethical to introduce yourself as a certification holder by listing it in your CV or profile headline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 11:15:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can get in touch with me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ninel-b/&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; or write me an email:&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;my_addr&#34;&gt;contact&lt;span style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;REMOVE&lt;/span&gt;@ninel&lt;!-- none --&gt;.work&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Ninel Bolotova</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 11:15:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Professionally, I mostly worked as a project manager with technical background, head of operations, and general problem preventer. I find joy and excitement in obtaining knowledge, solving challenges, and improving and applying my skills.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/workflow-setup-automation-expert-specialist-hire/&#34;&gt;offer workflow setup &amp;amp; automation services&lt;/a&gt; in Trello, Asana, Notion, ClickUp, and other PM software; using Make and Zapier for integrations and automating complex flows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The overall topic of this blog is &amp;ldquo;Personal Growth via Lifelong Learning&amp;rdquo; – you’ll see articles about self-education, remote work, certifications and continuous education, and other related subjects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Getting Certified Worth It? Do the Benefits Outweigh the Costs?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If the job you seek requires a license, then making a decision is easy – you don&amp;rsquo;t really have a choice. Licensure and certification are both means of verifying your skills and expertise, but they have some &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.differencebetween.net/language/words-language/difference-between-certification-and-licensure/&#34;&gt;distinct differences&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, a license is issued by a government authority and is legally required to practice in a field or hold a certain title. Certification is voluntary, serving as a reassurance to your peers and clients that you meet specific qualifications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
