<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Remote, Self-Education, No-Burnout &amp; More. Blog by Ninel Bolotova</title>
    <link>https://ninel.work/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Remote, Self-Education, No-Burnout &amp; More. Blog by Ninel Bolotova</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ninel.work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 11:15:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can get in touch with me on Twitter or LinkedIn, or write me an email: contactREMOVE@ninel.work</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work with me</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/work-with-ninel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 11:16:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/work-with-ninel/</guid>
      <description>I provide various services as a freelancer, including but not limited to:
project management creating and optimizing workflows in remote environment reviewing and hiring the best contractors in various fields implementing Agile methodologies setting up and customizing E-commerce stores, mainly Shopify productivity coaching Get in touch with me to book a free 30-min discovery call:
contactREMOVE@ninel.work</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Ninel Bolotova</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 11:15:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/about/</guid>
      <description>On this blog, I share articles about self-education, remote work, certifications and continuous education, and other related subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Getting Certified Worth It? Do the Benefits Outweigh the Costs?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>If the job you seek requires a license, then making a decision is easy – you don&amp;rsquo;t really have a choice. Licensure and certification are both means of verifying your skills and expertise, but they have some distinct differences.
In a nutshell, a license is issued by a government authority and is legally required to practice in a field or hold a certain title. Certification is voluntary, serving as a reassurance to your peers and clients that you meet specific qualifications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
