<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>courses on Remote, Self-Education, No-Burnout &amp; More. Blog by Ninel Bolotova</title>
    <link>https://ninel.work/tags/courses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in courses on Remote, Self-Education, No-Burnout &amp; More. Blog by Ninel Bolotova</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ninel.work/tags/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 6 Cybersecurity Certification Providers&#39; Recertification Costs</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/top-cybersecurity-providers-recertification-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/top-cybersecurity-providers-recertification-cost/</guid>
      <description>So, you decided that it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to get a cybersecurity certification. But which one should you go for?
While obtaining a certification is quite an endeavor, that’s only the first step. To keep it active, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to pay annual fees and submit continuous education units based on the issuers’ requirements. Otherwise, your hard-earned credential will expire, and it will be forbidden and unethical to introduce yourself as a certification holder by listing it in your CV or profile headline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Getting Certified Worth It? Do the Benefits Outweigh the Costs?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>If the job you seek requires a license, then making a decision is easy – you don&amp;rsquo;t really have a choice. Licensure and certification are both means of verifying your skills and expertise, but they have some distinct differences.
In a nutshell, a license is issued by a government authority and is legally required to practice in a field or hold a certain title. Certification is voluntary, serving as a reassurance to your peers and clients that you meet specific qualifications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
