<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>certifications on Remote, Self-Education, No-Burnout &amp; More. Blog by Ninel Bolotova</title>
    <link>https://ninel.work/categories/certifications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in certifications on Remote, Self-Education, No-Burnout &amp; More. Blog by Ninel Bolotova</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ninel.work/categories/certifications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Online Proctored Testing at Home: Pros &amp; Cons. Where to Take Your Exam?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/online-proctored-testing-pros-cons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/online-proctored-testing-pros-cons/</guid>
      <description>One of the silver linings to the 2020 COVID pandemic was that the certification providers became much more open to online testing. Now everyone offers this option, so you could take a test from the comfort of your own home.
There are a few caveats, though. I took my certification tests online, and I&amp;rsquo;ll likely continue to do so in the future. But every time at a certain point I wished I were in a test center instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 6 Cybersecurity Certification Providers&#39; Recertification Costs</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/top-cybersecurity-providers-recertification-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/top-cybersecurity-providers-recertification-cost/</guid>
      <description>So, you decided that it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to get a cybersecurity certification. But which one should you go for?
While obtaining a certification is quite an endeavor, that’s only the first step. To keep it active, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to pay annual fees and submit continuous education units based on the issuers’ requirements. Otherwise, your hard-earned credential will expire, and it will be forbidden and unethical to introduce yourself as a certification holder by listing it in your CV or profile headline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Getting Certified Worth It? Do the Benefits Outweigh the Costs?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>If the job you seek requires a license, then making a decision is easy – you don&amp;rsquo;t really have a choice. Licensure and certification are both means of verifying your skills and expertise, but they have some distinct differences.
In a nutshell, a license is issued by a government authority and is legally required to practice in a field or hold a certain title. Certification is voluntary, serving as a reassurance to your peers and clients that you meet specific qualifications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
