<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal growth on Personal and Professional Development via Life-Long Learning</title>
    <link>https://ninel.work/categories/personal-growth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal growth on Personal and Professional Development via Life-Long Learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ninel.work/categories/personal-growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Work-Life Balance or Integration? How to Maintain When WFH</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/find-maintain-work-life-balance-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/find-maintain-work-life-balance-home/</guid>
      <description>The question of work-life balance became especially topical when many people switched to working remotely.
How to maintain the balance between work and home lives when your home is your workplace? Is it possible to separate them? And is it necessary?..
Work from home, or WFH, is a blessing if managed successfully – but it requires a good deal of self-awareness, as well as making some conscious choices that aren’t always easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Rules of Effective Delegation of Tasks and Authority</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/effective-delegation-tasks-authority-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/effective-delegation-tasks-authority-workplace/</guid>
      <description>Are you the best guy or gal for the job?
I’m sure you’re qualified. But for the overall outcome, would it be best if you’re the one doing a certain task?
Successful delegation allows for more work to be done better, empowers others, and helps you maintain a healthy work-life balance.
Unsuccessful delegation leads to lots of rework, broken trust, and losses.
The ability to delegate is especially important for project managers, business owners, and other people in leadership positions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Burnout &amp; Mental Exhaustion: an Actionable Guide</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/burnout-mental-exhaustion-how-to-overcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/burnout-mental-exhaustion-how-to-overcome/</guid>
      <description>You’re depleted. You’ve had enough.
There’s barely any fuel left in your energy tank, so you’re squeezing blood out of your veins to keep the car of your life running for another mile.
Does it sound familiar?
In this article, we’ll discuss:
How to tell if you’re burned out Common burnout causes: what’s your primary cause? Strategies and tips for dealing with burnout How to recover from burnout mentally and physically photo by @tara-winstead on Pexels</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set and Maintain Healthy Boundaries: The Key Factors</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-set-maintain-develop-boundaries-strong-healthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-set-maintain-develop-boundaries-strong-healthy/</guid>
      <description>What are boundaries, and why are they so important for your personal and professional life success and satisfaction?
The laws of the state are explicit, and if someone breaks a law, they’ll be prosecuted.
Ethics and morale are widely agreed on in society, and if someone acts unethically, they’ll face social consequences.
But the individual, personal boundaries have no universal rules. There’s a consensus on some things: for example, asking strangers about their personal life is intrusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Consistency and Self-Discipline: 5 Actionable Tips</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-improve-consistency-tips-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-improve-consistency-tips-guide/</guid>
      <description>To achieve our goals, we need to do things repeatedly.
Practicing day after day to maintain and improve our professional skills and physical shape. Repeatedly saying &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to people who ask for more than we can – or are willing – to give at the moment. Constantly fighting destructive behaviors and habits. Success isn&amp;rsquo;t a one-time feat, it&amp;rsquo;s compounded from small building blocks. And the foundation for life success is consistency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to 10x Your Chances to Achieve Success in Life</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-life-success-factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-life-success-factors/</guid>
      <description>Without further ado, here&amp;rsquo;s the formula for achieving success in anything:
Success = Effort x Tools x Consistency x Talent x Mindset.
Ok, that looks vague. How do you actually use it in your life?
How do you improve each of those points to increase your chances of success tenfold or even much more?
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at each of the points in the formula and talk about some important conditions to use it efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 30-day Self-Improvement Challenge - Updated Monthly</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/self-improvement-challenge-personal-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/self-improvement-challenge-personal-growth/</guid>
      <description>Here’s the personal growth challenge for this month. What were your favorite and least favorite tasks? How many days did you complete? Do you have some ideas for the upcoming challenges?
Get in touch and let me know!
1. Don’t use your phone for 1 hour before going to bed Put down your phone and other electronic devices an hour before you plan to go to sleep. Mute all notifications so it doesn’t make sounds or buzz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing an Agile Mindset: Key Values and Principles Applied</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/develop-agile-mindset-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/develop-agile-mindset-guide/</guid>
      <description>Agile methodologies are successful when people involved share certain values and principles.
Agile mindset is an approach that focuses on learning, action, collaboration, adaptation, and innovation.
In this article, we’ll discuss what the Agile mindset is, how it’s different from Lean and Growth mindsets, and how it could be implemented beyond your workspace.
photo by @austindistel on Unsplash
CONTENTS &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; ⇅ Agile mindset vs. Growth mindset Fixed mindset: either you have talent or you don&amp;rsquo;t Waterfall methodology: a rigid, sequential approach Agile vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Intuition With Learning and Self-Awareness</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/develop-intuition-learning-self-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/develop-intuition-learning-self-awareness/</guid>
      <description>Does your &amp;ldquo;gut feeling&amp;rdquo; ever lie to you?
How many times did you wish you trusted your initial instinct? Or regretted the decision you made without thinking it through because at the moment it felt &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo;? Are you irritated that ` you keep overthinking things, and the opportunities slip away?
Intuition is a spontaneous insight without conscious reasoning. It&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily correct. But when we talk about developing intuition, the intent is learning to make quick judgments that would bring desirable outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
