<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal growth on Personal and Professional Development via Life-Long Learning</title>
    <link>https://ninel.work/categories/personal-growth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal growth on Personal and Professional Development via Life-Long Learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ninel.work/categories/personal-growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Work-Life Balance or Integration? How to Maintain When WFH</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/find-maintain-work-life-balance-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/find-maintain-work-life-balance-home/</guid>
      <description>The question of work-life balance became especially topical when many people switched to working remotely.
How to maintain the balance between work and home lives when your home is your workplace? Is it possible to separate them? And is it necessary?..
Work from home, or WFH, is a blessing if managed successfully – but it requires a good deal of self-awareness, as well as making some conscious choices that aren’t always easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Rules of Effective Delegation of Tasks and Authority</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/effective-delegation-tasks-authority-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/effective-delegation-tasks-authority-workplace/</guid>
      <description>Are you the best guy or gal for the job?
I’m sure you’re qualified. But for the overall outcome, would it be best if you’re the one doing a certain task?
Successful delegation allows for more work to be done better, empowers others, and helps you maintain a healthy work-life balance.
Unsuccessful delegation leads to lots of rework, broken trust, and losses.
The ability to delegate is especially important for project managers, business owners, and other people in leadership positions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Burnout &amp; Mental Exhaustion: an Actionable Guide</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/burnout-mental-exhaustion-how-to-overcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/burnout-mental-exhaustion-how-to-overcome/</guid>
      <description>You’re depleted. You’ve had enough.
There’s barely any fuel left in your energy tank, so you’re squeezing blood out of your veins to keep the car of your life running for another mile.
Does it sound familiar?
In this article, we’ll discuss:
How to tell if you’re burned out Common burnout causes: what’s your primary cause? Strategies and tips for dealing with burnout How to recover from burnout mentally and physically photo by @tara-winstead on Pexels</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to 10x Your Chances to Achieve Success in Life</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-life-success-factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-life-success-factors/</guid>
      <description>Without further ado, here&amp;rsquo;s the formula for achieving success in anything:
Success = Effort x Tools x Consistency x Talent x Mindset.
Ok, that looks vague. How do you actually use it in your life?
How do you improve each of those points to increase your chances of success tenfold or even much more?
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at each of the points in the formula and talk about some important conditions to use it efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
