<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal Growth on Personal and Professional Development via Life-Long Learning</title>
    <link>https://ninel.work/categories/personal-growth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal Growth on Personal and Professional Development via Life-Long Learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ninel.work/categories/personal-growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Year&#39;s Resolutions: How to Make Them Work</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/new-years-resolutions-fail-how-make-them-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/new-years-resolutions-fail-how-make-them-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard of “average Tuesday” resolutions: when one day you decide to turn your life around and never look back?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That works for some people, but “average Tuesday” resolutions, and even birthday resolutions, are far from a social phenomenon that New Year’s resolutions are. So what is it about the New Year that makes it so special?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;New Year is a milestone that we all experience together, so it feels like a more powerful turning point, a fresh start. Throwing the old calendar in the bin, you want to leave the old “you” behind in the last year, too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Can I Trust and not Get Burned? Red and Green Flags</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/who-to-trust-red-green-flags/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/who-to-trust-red-green-flags/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be great to live in a world where you never have to question others’ reliability and intentions?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the real world, however, we constantly need to gauge the trustworthiness of strangers and friends alike. Every new situation, every decision that involves another person is a leap of faith to some degree.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is there a way to tell for sure whether you can trust someone or not? While there’s no rule that would give a certain guarantee, there are points to look out for to minimize the chances of being fooled or disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impostor Syndrome: How to Overcome It for Good?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/impostor-syndrome-how-overcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/impostor-syndrome-how-overcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Impostor syndrome is more common than you might think. For all you know, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7174434/&#34;&gt;over half of your friends and colleagues&lt;/a&gt; might be experiencing it – and saying nothing, because, of course, they don’t want to be outed as impostors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The impostor phenomenon could be a big impediment to your career growth – or worse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being reluctant to raise your rates or ask for a promotion is one thing. But when a person works in an environment they hate, feeling like they got to that position by chance, and things will only get worse for them if they leave – that is dangerous for mental and even physical health.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Criticism at Work and at Home: How to Handle It Constructively</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-handle-deal-with-criticism-work-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-handle-deal-with-criticism-work-family/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes being told that their behavior is wrong, their work is incompetent, or their life choices are faulty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When those things are told in a rude, condescending manner, we like them even less.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How to deal with criticism at work and home and minimize its negative emotional impact?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And how to process every piece of criticism into valuable information that helps you grow as a professional and as a person?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work-Life Balance or Integration? How to Maintain When WFH</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/find-maintain-work-life-balance-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/find-maintain-work-life-balance-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The question of work-life balance became especially topical when many people switched to working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How to maintain the balance between work and home lives when your home &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; your workplace? Is it possible to separate them? And is it necessary?..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Work from home, or WFH, is a blessing if managed successfully – but it requires a good deal of self-awareness, as well as making some conscious choices that aren’t always easy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Rules of Effective Delegation of Tasks and Authority</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/effective-delegation-tasks-authority-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/effective-delegation-tasks-authority-workplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you the best guy or gal for the job?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you’re qualified. But for the overall outcome, would it be best if &lt;em&gt;you’re&lt;/em&gt; the one doing a  certain task?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Successful delegation allows for more work to be done better, empowers others, and helps you &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/find-maintain-work-life-balance-home/&#34;&gt;maintain a healthy work-life balance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unsuccessful delegation leads to lots of rework, broken trust, and losses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ability to delegate is especially important for project managers, business owners, and other people in leadership positions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Burnout &amp; Mental Exhaustion: an Actionable Guide</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/burnout-mental-exhaustion-how-to-overcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/burnout-mental-exhaustion-how-to-overcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You’re depleted. You’ve had enough.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There’s barely any fuel left in your energy tank, so you’re squeezing blood out of your veins to keep the car of your life running for another mile.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does it sound familiar?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll discuss:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How to tell if you’re burned out&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Common burnout causes: what’s your primary cause?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Strategies and tips for dealing with burnout&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How to recover from burnout mentally and physically&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/burnout-mental-exhaustion-how-to-overcome-hero.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;How to tell you&amp;#39;re burned out, and how to deal with and recover from a burnout?&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;photo by @tara-winstead on Pexels&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Set and Maintain Healthy Boundaries: The Key Factors</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-set-maintain-develop-boundaries-strong-healthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-set-maintain-develop-boundaries-strong-healthy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What are boundaries, and why are they so important for your personal and professional &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/articles/how-life-success-factors/&#34;&gt;life success and satisfaction&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The laws of the state are explicit, and if someone breaks a law, they’ll be &lt;strong&gt;prosecuted&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ethics and morale are widely agreed on in society, and if someone acts unethically, they’ll face &lt;strong&gt;social consequences&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But the individual, personal boundaries have no universal rules. There’s a consensus on some things: for example, asking strangers about their personal life is intrusive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Consistency and Self-Discipline: 5 Actionable Tips</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-improve-consistency-tips-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-improve-consistency-tips-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To achieve our goals, we need to do things repeatedly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practicing day after day&lt;/strong&gt; to maintain and improve our professional skills and physical shape.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repeatedly saying &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; to people who ask for more than we can – or are willing – to give at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constantly fighting&lt;/strong&gt; destructive behaviors and habits.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Success isn&amp;rsquo;t a one-time feat, it&amp;rsquo;s compounded from small building blocks. And the foundation for life success is consistency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to 10x Your Chances to Achieve Success in Life</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-life-success-factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-life-success-factors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, here&amp;rsquo;s the formula for achieving success in anything:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success = Effort x Tools x Consistency x Talent x Mindset&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ok, that looks vague. How do you actually use it in your life?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How do you improve each of those points to increase your chances of success tenfold or even much more?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at each of the points in the formula and talk about some important conditions to use it efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A 30-day Self-Improvement Challenge - Updated Monthly</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/self-improvement-challenge-personal-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/self-improvement-challenge-personal-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s the personal growth challenge for this month. What were your favorite and least favorite tasks? How many days did you complete? Do you have some ideas for the upcoming challenges?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ninel.work/contact/&#34;&gt;Get in touch&lt;/a&gt; and let me know!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;pinnable&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/30-day-personal-growth-self-improvement-development-challenge.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;A 30-day self-growth challenge for this month&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-dont-use-your-phone-for-1-hour-before-going-to-bed&#34;&gt;1. Don’t use your phone for 1 hour before going to bed&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Put down your phone and other electronic devices an hour before you plan to go to sleep. Mute all notifications so it doesn’t make sounds or buzz.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing an Agile Mindset: Key Values and Principles Applied</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/develop-agile-mindset-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/develop-agile-mindset-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agile methodologies are successful when people involved share certain values and principles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agile mindset is an approach that focuses on learning, action, collaboration, adaptation, and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll discuss what the Agile mindset is, how it’s different from Lean and Growth mindsets, and how it could be implemented beyond your workspace.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ninel.work/article_images/develop-agile-mindset-guide-hero.jpg&#34;&#xA;         alt=&#34;What is the Agile mindset and how to develop it? How is it different from Lean and Growth mindsets?&#34;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;photo by @austindistel on Unsplash&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing Intuition With Learning and Self-Awareness</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/develop-intuition-learning-self-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/develop-intuition-learning-self-awareness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Does your &amp;ldquo;gut feeling&amp;rdquo; ever lie to you?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How many times did you wish you trusted your initial instinct? Or regretted the decision you made without thinking it through because at the moment it felt &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo;? Are you irritated that ` you keep overthinking things, and the opportunities slip away?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Intuition is a spontaneous insight without conscious reasoning. It&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily correct. But when we talk about developing intuition, the intent is learning to make quick judgments that would bring desirable outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
