<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Services on Personal and Professional Development via Life-Long Learning</title>
    <link>https://ninel.work/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Services on Personal and Professional Development via Life-Long Learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ninel.work/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hire a ClickUp Expert – Advanced Workflow Setup &amp; Automation</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/services/hire-clickup-expert-workspace-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/services/hire-clickup-expert-workspace-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you planning to migrate to ClickUp from another project management platform? Or is this your team’s first time using a PM tool for collaboration, and you need help getting started?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or maybe you&amp;rsquo;re already using ClickUp and want to streamline your operations with automation?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m Ninel, a workflow architect and integration specialist. I work with individuals and companies to design, optimize, and automate processes in ClickUp and other project management tools, solving challenges and improving efficiency every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hire a Monday.com Expert – Personalized Workflow Setup &amp; Automation</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/services/hire-monday-expert-setup-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninel.work/services/hire-monday-expert-setup-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you planning to move to Monday.com from another project management software? Or is it the first PM tool your team is about to use for collaboration, and you&amp;rsquo;re looking for assistance with the initial setup?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps you’d like to streamline your current processes in Monday with automation?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m Ninel, a workflow architect and integration expert. I help individuals and companies set up and optimize their process flows in Monday.com and other project management tools, and solve various challenges along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
