<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>psm on Remote, Self-Education, No-Burnout &amp; More. Blog by Ninel Bolotova</title>
    <link>https://ninel.work/tags/psm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in psm on Remote, Self-Education, No-Burnout &amp; More. Blog by Ninel Bolotova</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ninel.work/tags/psm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Find the Best Online Course for You? 6 Points to Consider</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-find-best-online-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-find-best-online-course/</guid>
      <description>There are so many courses out there: free and paid, instructor-led and self-paced, lasting from a few hours to a few weeks or months.
Whatever topic you&amp;rsquo;re looking for, you&amp;rsquo;ll find dozens of courses. Even if the topic is obscure, you&amp;rsquo;ll likely find more than one.
How do you choose which one to go with? If it&amp;rsquo;s a paid course, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to gamble your money, but free courses require investments as well – your time and energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Pass the Certification Exam on the First Try – Study Tips</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/how-pass-certification-exam-test-first-try-tips-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/how-pass-certification-exam-test-first-try-tips-techniques/</guid>
      <description>So, you figured out why you want to get certified, checked and compared the options, and chose a credential you want to pursue. It would be great to pass the test the first time you attempt it. Is there a way to prepare that would guarantee such success?
I&amp;rsquo;m not giving you a 100% success guarantee (and you should be wary of people who claim they do). But I&amp;rsquo;ll share an approach that would increase your chances greatly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Getting Certified Worth It? Do the Benefits Outweigh the Costs?</title>
      <link>https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninel.work/articles/are-certifications-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>If the job you seek requires a license, then making a decision is easy – you don&amp;rsquo;t really have a choice. Licensure and certification are both means of verifying your skills and expertise, but they have some distinct differences.
In a nutshell, a license is issued by a government authority and is legally required to practice in a field or hold a certain title. Certification is voluntary, serving as a reassurance to your peers and clients that you meet specific qualifications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
